Guide to the Davida Catherine French Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Davida Catherine French papers
1906-1974
1906-1907
SC0201
French, Davida Catherine.
0.5 Linear feet
Class notes, exams, essays, and creative writing assignments from English classes at Stanford University, 1906-07; several of the creative writing assignments pertain to Japan, where she taught before attending Stanford University; and notes and exam from a philosophy course with William James, 1906. Collection also includes a copy of NOT INCLUDED IN A SHEEPSKIN: STANFORD STORIES (1907), which she co-authored with Esther Stevens and Laura Wells.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Davida ("Vida") Catherine French was born in 1880 in San Francisco, the daughter of Dr. Hayes Clifton French, one of San Francisco's first opthalmologists. After graduation from Lowell High School in San Francisco, she attended Mills College in Oakland. She transferred from Mills to Stanford, graduating in 1908 from Stanford with an A.B. in history.
Prior to her graduation form Stanford, Ms. French spent some time in Japan, where she taught Latin and Greek in the Japanese school system. While in the Orient, Ms. French met Charles William Ure, a Scotsman engaged in business in Shanghai; they were married in London in 1913. After Mr. Ure's death in Shanghai in 1923, Mrs. Ure returned to England. For many years, she alternated residences between Malaga, Spain, Tunbridge Wells, England, and Palo Alto.
While at Stanford, Mrs. Ure had been a member of the Cap and Gown scholastic honor society and a member of Alpha Phi sorority. She was also a member of the Palo Alto Women's Club and the American Association of University Women.
Mrs. Ure died in Palo Alto in 1974 at the age of 94. In her will, Mrs. Ure established a medical scholarship at Stanford in her father's name.
Description of the Collection
Class notes, exams, essays, and creative writing assignments from English classes at Stanford University, 1906-07; several of the creative writing assignments pertain to Japan, where she taught before attending Stanford University; and notes and exam from a philosophy course with William James, 1906. Collection also includes a copy of NOT INCLUDED IN A SHEEPSKIN: STANFORD STORIES (1907), which she co-authored with Esther Stevens and Laura Wells.
Access Terms
French, Davida Catherine.; James, William, 1842-1910; Stanford University. Department of English.; Stevens, Esther.; Wells, Laura.; English literature; Japan in literature.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - English 22: Class assignments, 1906-1907 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Tragic Five Acts of Byron's Life" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Keat's Ode to a Nightingale and Ode to a Grecian Man" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Romanticism of Coleridge" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Women in 'Childe Harold's Pilgrimage" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "A Comparison of Shelley's 'Prometheus Unbound' and the "Prometheus Bound' of Aeschylus" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Aspects of the Doctrine of Immortality in Wordsworth" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - English 22: creative writing assignments, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Feel of Solitude" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Manuscript of Monsieur" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "O Yuko San" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Treasure of the Humble" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "A Ball Room Incident" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Thanksgiving" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "A Strength in the By-Ways" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Uncouth Van Uston" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Approach to Japan" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Chummy's Inheritance" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - English 19: class notes and exams, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - First lecture, January 9th (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "A Comparison of Arudd's Tristan and Iseult and Tennyson's Last Tournament" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Childhood in Swinbourne's Poems" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "The Philosophy of Empedocles on Etna" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Mycerinus: Its Purpose" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "The Blessed Damozel" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exam, April 15, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exam, May 1, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exam questions handout, May 13, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Not Included in a Sheepskin: Stanford Stories by Davida French, Esther Stevens, Laura Well. Stanford: Stanford Book Store, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Notes and an exam from philosophy course taught by William James, Spring 1906 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Obituary, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)